Test 4. This is the IELTS listening test.
You will hear a number of different recordings
and you will have to answer questions on what you hear.
There will be time for you to read the instructions and questions
and you will have a chance to check your work.
All the recordings will be played once only.
The test is in four parts.
At the end of the test you will be given 10 minutes
to transfer your answers to the answer sheet.
Now turn to part 1.
Part 1. You will hear a man phoning to enquire
about a cleaning service for his apartment.
First you have some time to look at questions 1 to 5.
Now listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 5.
Hello, Easy Life Cleaning Services, Jacinta speaking.
Oh, hello. I'm looking for a cleaning service for my apartment.
Do you do domestic cleaning?
Sure.
Well, it's just a one-bedroom flat.
Do you have a basic cleaning package?
Yes. For a one-bedroom flat,
we're probably looking at about two hours for a clean,
so we'd do a thorough clean of all surfaces in each room
and polish them where necessary.
Does your apartment have carpets?
No, I don't have any, but the floor would need cleaning.
Of course, we'd do that in every room
and we'd do a thorough clean of the kitchen and bathroom.
OK.
Then we have some additional services,
which you can request if you want.
So, for example, we can clean your oven for you every week.
Actually, I hardly ever use that, but can you do the fridge?
Sure. Would you like that done every week?
Yes, definitely.
And would ironing clothes be an additional service you can do?
Yes, of course.
It wouldn't be much, just my shirts for work that week.
That's fine.
And we could also clean your microwave if you want.
No, I wipe that out pretty regularly, so there's no need for that.
We also offer additional services
that you might want a bit less often, say every month.
So, for example,
if the inside of your windows need cleaning, we could do that.
Yes, that'd be good.
I'm on the 15th floor,
so the outside gets done regularly by specialists,
but the inside does get a bit grubby.
And we could arrange for your curtains to get cleaned if necessary.
No, they're OK.
But would you be able to do something about the balcony?
It's quite small and I don't use it much,
but it could do with a wash every month or so.
Yes, we can get the pressure washer onto that.
Before you hear the rest of the conversation,
you have some time to look at questions 6 to 10.
Now listen and answer questions 6 to 10.
Now, if you're interested,
we do offer some other possibilities to do with general maintenance.
For example, if you have a problem with water
and you need a plumber in a hurry,
we can put you in touch with a reliable one
who can come out straight away.
And the same thing if you need an electrician.
Right, that's good to know.
I've only just moved here,
so I don't have any of those sorts of contacts.
And I don't know if this is of interest to you,
but we also offer a special vacuum cleaning system
which can improve the indoor air quality of your home
by capturing up to 99% of all the dust in the air.
So if you're troubled by allergies, this can make a big difference.
Right. In fact, I don't have that sort of problem,
but I'll bear it in mind.
Now, can you tell me a bit about your cleaning staff?
Of course.
So all our cleaners are very carefully selected.
When they apply to us,
they have to undergo a security check with the police
to make sure they don't have any sort of criminal background.
And of course, they have to provide references as well.
Then if we think they might be suitable for the job,
we give them training for it.
That lasts for two weeks, so it's very thorough,
and at the end of it, they have a test.
If they pass that, we take them on,
but we monitor them very carefully.
We ask all our clients to complete a review of their performance
after every visit and to email it to us
so we can pick up any problems straightaway and deal with them.
OK. Well, that all sounds good.
And will I always have the same cleaner?
Yes. We do our best to organise it that way
and we usually manage it.
Good. That's fine.
Right, so I'd like to go ahead and...
That is the end of Part 1.
You now have half a minute to check your answers to Part 1.
Thank you.